The world ends, Godzilla begins.
Godzilla is a action, drama, science fiction film directed by Gareth Edwards.
Ford Brody, a Navy bomb expert, has just reunited with his family in San Francisco
when he is forced to go to Japan to help his estranged father, Joe.
Soon, both men are swept up in an escalating crisis when an ancient alpha predator arises from
the sea to combat malevolent adversaries that threaten the survival of humanity.
The creatures leave colossal destruction in their wake, as they make
their way toward their final battleground: San Francisco.
Ford Brody, played by Aaron Taylor-Johnson.
Elle Brody, played by Elizabeth Olsen.
Sandra Brody, played by Juliette Binoche.
Joe Brody, played by Bryan Cranston.
Dr. Ishiro Serizawa, played by Ken Watanabe.
Dr. Vivienne Graham, played by Sally Hawkins.
Godzilla is a 2014 American monster film directed by Gareth Edwards.
Produced by Legendary Pictures and distributed by Warner Bros.
Pictures, it is a reboot of Toho's Godzilla franchise, the first film in Legendary's
Monsterverse franchise, and the 30th film in the Godzilla franchise.
The film stars Aaron Taylor-Johnson, Ken Watanabe, Elizabeth Olsen, Juliette
Binoche, Sally Hawkins, David Strathairn, and Bryan Cranston.
In the film, an American soldier attempts to return to his family while caught in the crossfire
of an ancient rivalry between Godzilla and two parasitic monsters known as MUTOs.
An early iteration of the project began in 2004 under executive producer Yoshimitsu Banno as a short IMAX 3D
film, but was transferred to Legendary in 2009 to be redeveloped as a full-length feature.
The film was announced in March 2010 and Edwards was
announced as the director in January 2011.
Principal photography began in March 2013 in the United
States and Canada and ended in July 2013.
Godzilla was theatrically released on May 16, 2014.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics, who praised the direction, visual effects, music, cinematography, respect to the
source material, and Cranston's performance, but criticized the script, characters, and Godzilla's insufficient screen time.
The film was a box office success, grossing $529.1 million worldwide against a production budget of $160
million, print and advertisement costs of $100 million, and a break-even point of $380 million.
The film's success prompted Toho to produce a reboot of their own (Toho's Shin Godzilla was released
in 2016), and Legendary to proceed with sequels and a shared cinematic franchise.
A sequel, Godzilla: King of the Monsters, was released on May 31, 2019.
The film explores themes of japan, monster, san
francisco, california, hawaii, giant monster.
The tone is emotional and thought_provoking.